<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Catnekaise</title>
    <link>https://catnekaise.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Catnekaise</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://catnekaise.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developer Notes</title>
      <link>https://catnekaise.github.io/ghrawel/developer-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://catnekaise.github.io/ghrawel/developer-notes/</guid>
      <description>ghrawel, because naming is hard.&#xA;My motivation for creating this was partially because of the cancelled feature service-tokens (temporary GitHub access tokens should be much easier than what it is today) and to explore if a cdk library can be viable when an application is required.&#xA;Hopefully documentation in catnekaise/ghrawel should answer most questions. If any issues please post an issue in that repository.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catnekaise</title>
      <link>https://catnekaise.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://catnekaise.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Open source scoped at GitHub integrations, AWS and potentially some other stuff. Some more in the works I hope to release soon. Feel free to contribute.&#xA;Naming is hard. In Sweden, we have a mountain named Kebnekaise. I changed Keb to Cat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cognito Identity in GitHub Actions</title>
      <link>https://catnekaise.github.io/github-actions-abac-aws/cognito-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://catnekaise.github.io/github-actions-abac-aws/cognito-identity/</guid>
      <description>This article compares authentication from GitHub Actions to AWS using the standard way passing the GitHub Actions OIDC Access Token to AWS STS compared to passing the same token to AWS Cognito Identity.&#xA;GitHub Actions OIDC Access Token When we authenticate with AWS STS using the GitHub Actions OIDC Access Token as explained here, we do it with a token having claims similar to below. (Example of full access token here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions ABAC in AWS - Detailed Explanation</title>
      <link>https://catnekaise.github.io/github-actions-abac-aws/detailed-explanation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://catnekaise.github.io/github-actions-abac-aws/detailed-explanation/</guid>
      <description>This is an article containing contextual/behavioural information related to GitHub Actions, Amazon Cognito Identity, AWS IAM, AWS STS and their interaction together. This could help when troubleshooting something that is not working or help you understand how a specific part in all of this works.&#xA;This article is not a setup guide nor a starting point. Have a look here if you are just starting out with this topic.&#xA;Note It&amp;rsquo;s very important to limit which entities in GitHub Actions are allowed to assume roles in your AWS Account(s).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup Amazon Cognito Identity for GitHub Actions - Enhanced AuthFlow</title>
      <link>https://catnekaise.github.io/github-actions-abac-aws/setup-using-aws-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://catnekaise.github.io/github-actions-abac-aws/setup-using-aws-console/</guid>
      <description>This guide will create an Amazon Cognito Identity Pool that allows GitHub Actions to authenticate using OpenID Connect. We&amp;rsquo;ll be using the Enhanched (Simplified) AuthFlow. We will also create a S3 Bucket so that we can test the attribute-based access control (ABAC) from the GitHub Actions workflow.&#xA;Note It&amp;rsquo;s very important to limit which entities in GitHub Actions are allowed to assume roles in your AWS Account(s). Misconfiguration in either AWS IAM Role trust policies or a Cognito Identity Pool could lead to every organization and user in GitHub being allowed access to your AWS resources from GitHub Actions.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
